Before getting started on this function, I'm going to think about
،قبل البدء في هذه الدالة سأفكر في كيفية
how I would calculate the overall completion rate for a single country.
حساب .معدل الإكمال الشامل لدولة واحدة
So let's say i have these two values for a female and male completion rate.
ولهذا لنفترض أن لدي هاتين القيمتين .لمعدل إكمال خاص بالإناث والذكور
To get the overall completion rate, I would add up these two values and
،للحصول على معدل الإكمال الشامل قد أُضيف هاتين القيمتين
divide by two.
.وأقسم الناتج على اثنين
Sure enough, that looks like it worked.
.ونجح الأمر بالتأكيد كما أرى
Now because of Numpy's vectorized operations,
والآن، بفضل عمليات التحويل إلى رسومات المتجهات في صفائف Numpy، يمكنني أن
I can actually use this exact same line of code for arrays.
أستخدم سطر التعليمة البرمجية هذا نفسه .للصفائف
To demonstrate that,
،وللتوضيح
I'll show the results on these shorter arrays with data for only 20 countries.
سأعرض نتائج هذه الصفائف الأقصر مع بيانات .تخص 20 دولة فقط
First, if I add the two arrays together, I get an array with
،أولاً، إذا أضفتُ الصفيفين سويًا سأحصل على صفيف
the sum of the female and male completion rate for each country.
بمجموع معدل الإكمال للإناث والذكور .لكل دولة
So each element in the resulting array is the sum
ولهذا يمثل كل عنصر في الصفيف الناتج مجموعة
of the corresponding elements from the two previous arrays.
العناصر الموافقة .من الصفيفين السابقين
I'll name this array total_array.
.وسأُطلق على هذا الصفيف اسم total_array
Then if I divide the total array by two, I get an array where each element
وبعد ذلك، إذا قسمت الصفيف الإجمالي على اثنين، سأحصل على صفيف يمثل كل عنصر به نصف
is half of the corresponding element from total array.
العنصر المكافئ .من الصفيف الإجمالي
This is the result I wanted, so I'll scroll up and fill in my function.
وهذه هي النتيجة التي أردت الحصول عليها، ولهذا السبب .سأقوم بالتمرير لأعلى وتعبئة الدالة ،
So the code for this function is return (female_completion +
ولهذا فإن التعليمة البرمجية لهذه الدالة هي returnأي ((female_completion +
male_completion) / 2.
.male_completion) / 2
And just like when doing arithmetic on single numbers,
وعلى غرار القيام بعمليات حسابية ،على الأرقام الفردية
adding parentheses is important.
.من المهم إضافة الأقواس